Guide to the Winterhouse Art and Design Collection of Corporate Clients
Yale University Arts Library
Winterhouse Art and Design collection of corporate clients
1962-2012
1990-2012
ART 24
Yale University Arts Library
1.25
(3 boxes)
The collection contains a variety of corporate publications, including annual reports and other promotional materials.
Drenttel, William, 1953-2013
Helfand, Jessica, 1960-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of William Drenttel and Jessica Helfand, 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Winterhouse was a design consultancy founded by partners William Drenttel and Jessica Helfand. According to their website, "Winterhouse Studio focuse[d] on editorial development and online media; cultural and educational institutions; and social innovation initiatives... Winterhouse Institute focuse[d] on non-profit, self-initiated projects that support design education as well as social and political initiatives."
Scope and Contents
The collection contains a variety of corporate publications, including annual reports and other promotional materials, collected by William Drenttel and Jessica Helfand in the course of their work as principals of Winterhouse Design and later Winterhouse Institute.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Annual Reports, 1991-2001. II. Paper Company Promotional Booklets, 1990-2011. III. Miscellaneous, 1962-2012.
Design; Annual reports; Promotional materials
- Annual Reports, 1991-2000; Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by company or corporate body.
  - Berkshire Hathaway Inc. 1990 annual report / Berkshire Hathaway Inc., 1991; 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chicago Board of Trade. The future belongs to you. The 1998 annual report of the Chicago Board of Trade., 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - GATX Capital. GATX Capital annual report, undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Herman Miller, Inc. 1997 annual report. Herman Miller, Inc., 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lila Wallace-Reader's Digest Fund. 1995 annual report. Lila Wallace-Reader's Digest Fund, 1996; 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mead Annual Report Show. The Mead Annual Report Show 1993., undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Molecular Biosystems, Inc. Annual report 1. Molecular Biosystems, Inc., undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - National Audubon Society. Birds Wildlife & Habitat. National Audubon Society 1995 Annual Report, undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Razorfish. Everything that can be digital will be. 1999, Razorfish., 2000; 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Rockefeller Foundation. The Rockefeller Foundation 1992 annual report, 1993; 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Paper Company Promotional Booklets, 1990-2011; Series II
  - Champion. Blout, Jim. Champion: 100 years of papermaking in Hamilton, Ohio., 1994; 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fox River Paper, Co. From Company Profile to the Bottom Line. Fox River Paper, Co., 1993; 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Island Paper Mills. Luna. Island Paper Mills., 1996; 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Koninklijk Verbond van Grafische Ondernemingen. Koninklijk Verbond van Grafische Ondernemingen. Berlin, Gerard. Olie is onschuldig, olie is een zegen, olie is een plaag: een verhaal in beelden., 1990; 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mohawk Paper Mills, Inc. Mohawk Paper Mills, Inc. Mohawk Your Name Here 59, 1998; 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Mohawk Paper Mills, Inc. Found. Perdido. Verloren. S.l.: Mohawk Fine Papers, 1996; 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Potlatch Corporation. The 1997 Potlatch Annual Report Show, The Essentials, 1 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Potlatch Corporation. [Up.] Potlatch Corporation, 2001; 1 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Sappi Fine Paper. 10401: ten ideas that matter. Sappi Fine Paper North America, 2009; 1 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Sappi Fine Paper. Sappi Ideas that Matter, 2011; 1 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Stora Enso. New models for growth and profitability. Stora Enso, undated; 1 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Strathmore Paper. Roseman, Mill. The Strathmore century: the 100h anniversary issue of The Strathmorea. Strathmore Paper, International Paper Company, 1992., 1 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Miscellaneous, 1962-2012; Series III
  - Citigroup Inc. Caroline Cole: voted CEO of the year for creating the fastest growing brand in history. Citigroup Inc., 2009; 1 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Citigroup Inc. [Citi look book.] Citigroup Inc., 2009; 1 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Cranbrook Academy of Art. Graduate Studies catalogue. Cranbrook Academy of Art, undated; 1 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Delineodesign. Words & works. Delineodesign, 2012., 1 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Helen Hamlyn Centre for Design. Chen, Andy. Imaging intimacy: challenging stereotypes of age, sex & health., 2010; 1 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Illinois, University of. Four major addresses and panel discussion ... delivered at the annual meeting held at the University of Illinois, March 17, 1962 / edited by Edward J. Zagorski. [IL: Industrial Design Education Association, University of Illinois], 1 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - International Business Machines Corporation. The adventure of tomorrow. S.l.: International Business Machines Corporation, undated; 1 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Merrill Lynch. Rules of employment. Merrill Lynch, [1985]; 1 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Pratt Institute. Live, learn, and design. Pratt Graduate Communications & Package Design. (also includes 8 bookplates), 2012; 1 (Box 3, Folder 31)